# **Dharmendra K Patel**

# **Maintenance Engineer**

Phone: +918866519311

Email: <a href="mailto:dhavalpatel3402@gmail.com">dhavalpatel3402@gmail.com</a> Address: B/203, Krushnam Status,

> Anand Party Plot Road, New Ranip, Ahmedabad

#### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

To work for suitable assignment in an organization, which provides excellent work culture. To explore my professional and technical skills for personal and organizational growth.

# **SUMMARY**

Dedicated and pro-active Maintenance Engineer with 6 years of experience in Plant, On-site and In-house Maintenance of Machinery, mechanical products and Special purpose machine. Able to work under pressure in fast-paced, time-sensitive environments, excellent analytical and Problem-solving skills.

Highly experienced in identifying needed improvements in existing design and planning for development of new product or improving the existing system by using cost effective way of development.

## **KEY SKILLS/TECHNICAL SKILLS**

5S, Kaizen, CAPA, GR&R, Training & Development, ISO Documentation, Innovation, Customer Complain Solving Resolution, Effective team member, Fast leaner.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Siddhi Engineers, Vadsar, Gandhinagar (Siddhi Group)

Manufacturer, supplier and Exporter of precision drawn Aluminum Tubes.

Position: -Maintenance cum Innovation Engineer

Period: - January 2019 - till date

- Responsible for all Maintenance processes In-house and On-site.
- Coordinated Plant Maintenance planning among General Manager, Quality manager, operation heads, and customers.
- Responsible for the day-to-day maintenance of Plant machinery and maintain standards set by the company for smooth operation of Plant machinery.
- To look after complete maintenance of service equipments like Air Compressor, Chiller, Vacuum pump, ETP plant, ETC.
- Provide training to the team or individuals to overcome their weaknesses towards work.
- Conduct internal audits in factory and submit audit reports to top management for review.
- Supervise mechanical work related to machine maintenance.
- Follow PDCA cycle for all development and routine work in Innovation Department.
- Provide customer service and support to sales & marketing department for On-site maintenance.
- Ensure ISO documentation and internal audit reports.
- Responsible for systematic planning of the job to enable timely mobilization of Resources- Men, Material, Machinery.
- Work as per Measure, Analyze & Improve (MAI).
- Do Maintenance of Plant machinery as per Clean, Lubrication, Inspection, Tightening (CLIT) criteria and followed by operator everyday before machine start-up.
- Maintain Records as per requirements of ISO 9001, ISO 14001 and AS 9100D.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# JAY AMBE ENGINEERING CO. (JEC PUMPS & BIOGAS TECHNOLOGIES LTD.), Ahmedabad

Manufacturer, supplier and exporter of Chemical process pumps, Agitators and biogas plants.

**Position: - Quality cum Maintenance Engineer** 

Period: - June 2015 - December 2018

- Responsible for Inspection of all parts manufactured in-house and at vendors and foundries.
- Prepare QAPs, control plan, SOPs for Quality department.
- Check and ensure the quality of the product as per Customer's requirement.
- Handle Third party inspection and prepare reports as per standard requirements.
- Responsible for Testing of pumps and agitators as per requirement of customer as per pump testing standard IS5120.
- Casting Die and pattern inspection as per standard drawings.
- Responsible for the day-to-day maintenance of Plant machinery and maintain standards set by the company for smooth operation of Plant machinery.
- Implement concept of Preventive and Autonomous maintenance in our manufacturing units.
- Visit foundries and vendor parties for inspection and guide them for maintain quality of casting parts and machining parts as per requirements.
- Responsible for maintenance of pumps In-house and customer site.
- Responsible for customer complaint of pumps at site after installation.
- Prepare and maintain records for quality and maintenance department as per requirements of ISO 9001.

### RBD Engineers, Khatraj, Gandhinagar.

Manufacturer, supplier and exporter of various types of clutch plates, gear box and control systems.

Position: - Jr. Q.C. Engineer (As a trainee)

Period: - January 2015 - May 2015

- Responsible for Quality of product manufactured in CNC and VMC department.
- In-house inspection and document preparation for ISO audits.
- Submit daily inspection reports to Quality manager for maintain quality of products and audits
- Development of new gauges for easy and quick inspection of products to meet daily inspection plans.
- Maintain record as per requirements of ISO/TS 16949.

#### Flowchem Industries, Rakanpur, Ahmedabad.

**Position: - Production and planning Engineer** 

Period: - October 2010 - May 2012

- Small size Valves Planning Engineer.
- Jr. Machine shop Shift In charge.
- Maintain records as per requirements of API 6D, ISO 9001.

#### **EDUCATION**

B.E. (Mechanical) from Govt. Engineering College, Patan in 2014 from GTU, Gujarat.

Diploma in Mechanical Engineering from Govt. Polytechnic, Jamnagar in 2010 from TEB, Gujarat.

S. S. C. from GSHSEB, Gandhinagar in 2007.

#### **CERTIFICATES/PROJECTS**

- Accomplished the online certification course of "Lean Six Sigma Green Belt" by CBEPL.
- Accomplished the online certification course of "Kaizen champion" by CBEPL
- Accomplished the online certification course of "Problem Solving Tools" (7QC TOOLS) by STAT MODELLER.
- I have done Major Project on "Foot operated hydraulic lift" in B.E.
- I have done Project on "Development and efficiency improvement of desert cooler" in Diploma.

## **ACHIVEMENTS**

- Successful Development of Drill JIGS & FIXTURES for Axial Flow pumps IN JEC Pumps.
- Development of Semi-Automatic Pump Casing Hydro Test Batch in JEC Pumps.
- Implementation of 5S in Store Department for Easy identification of parts and For FIFO system.

## **SOFTWARE SKILL**

- AutoCAD 2D
- Office Suite: MS Word, MS Excel, MS PowerPoint
- Krishna IS 5120 (Pump Testing software)
- GODREJ ERP (Basics)

# **PERSONAL TRAITS**

- Innovative and Logical Thinking.
- Co-operative and enthusiastic.
- Learn new things.
- Supportive nature.
- Flexible
- Communication skill.

# **PERSONAL PARTICULARS**

Name	Dharmendrakumar Kantilal Patel
Date of Birth	May 19 <sup>th</sup> , 1992
Languages Known	English, Hindi and Gujarati
Gender	Male
Marital Status	Single
Address	B/203, Krushnam Status, opp. Sitaram avenue, Anand Party
	Plot Road, New Ranip, Ahmedabad-382480.

#### **DECLARATION**

I hereby declare that all the information given above is true to the best of my knowledge. PLACE:

YoursFaithfully

(DHARMENDRA.K.PATEL)